KAITLYN FERNELIUS

(801) 712-9403

kkin001@gmail.com

github.com/K-Fernie | linkedin.com/in/kaitlyn-fernelius-590ab6103/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Development Engineer with Bachelor's degree in computer science and 8+ years of proven experience in supporting cross-functional teams. Focused on increasing customer satisfaction through process improvements and technical support. Exceptional knowledge of developing strategic plans for service excellence, troubleshooting systems, efficiency, and quality management across various environments. Possess a comprehensive background in information technology, security, and software with a passion for driving brand awareness and product performance.

- Angular
- Java/SpringBoot
- HTML/CSS/TypeScript/JavaScript
- Python

- AWS
- GCP
- Openshift
- GitLab

- XP Pair Programming
- Agile
- Salesforce
- CompTia Security+

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kohl's Technology | Remote

Software Engineer, Amazon Fulfillment Technologies

May 2022 – March 2023

- Built and enhanced a Merchandise Planning app using Java, Angular, and TypeScript, collaborating across teams to integrate new features and enhance user experience
- Successfully implemented Redis in the backend architecture, resulting in a significant performance boost for the application, improving response times and overall efficiency.
- Acted as the primary engineer responsible for debugging and resolving issues within the Merchandise Planning application. Additionally, championed the adoption of Extreme Programming (XP) practices within the team and contributed to setting technology standards across the organization at Kohl's.

Amazon | Remote

May 2022 - March 2023

Software Engineer, Amazon Fulfillment Technologies

- Worked to develop back-end solutions for SOX compliance software by building efficient data processing solutions utilizing Java hosted on Native AWS platforms.
- Developed a UAT testing tool that increased onboarding efficiency for new Amazon Fulfillment Centers by 25%.
- During apprentice training built 2d Pixel art computer game using Java and swing, and learned machine learning systems with python.

Accenture | Nashville, TN

Aug 2021 – May 2022

Software Engineering Associate, Accenture Salesforce Team

- Developed back-end Salesforce automation solutions using Apex and Flows to assist with COVID contact tracing for the state of Kansas.
- Built a Salesforce solution for a non-profit client that increased their productivity and efficiency by 20%.
- Trained new Salesforce engineers to learn efficiently and build on the platform while developing technical skills needed to support client needs.

Nelson Laboratories, LLC | Clarksville, TN

Jan 2019 – Aug 2021

Document Control Specialist

- Established efficient workflow process for a leading global provider of laboratory testing and expert advisory services for MedTech and pharmaceutical companies, monitored productivity and implemented modifications
- Ensured data entry and accuracy, maintained a deep understanding of the quality system of document

- control and proactively, worked to mitigate any error that could occur within the document control processes.
- Aided and assisted lab technicians, created the written and archival of testing procedures and associated forms

EDUCATION | CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Software Development | Western Governors University | Spring 2022

Associate of Science (A.S.), Philosophy | Utah Valley University | 2019

Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I ITIL Foundation v4 CompTIA A+ | Oct 2020 CompTIA Sec+ | Jan 2021

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Software Languages: Java, Python, SQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript Cloud Platforms: Mongo, Openshift, Salesforce, GCP, AWS Operating Systems: Apple, Windows, Linux